<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking of Real Estate</title>
    <link>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org</link>
    <description />
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:52:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <!--National Association of REALTORS®-->
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SpeakingOfRealEstate" />
    <feedburner:info uri="speakingofrealestate" />
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <feedburner:emailServiceId>SpeakingOfRealEstate</feedburner:emailServiceId>
    <feedburner:feedburnerHostname>https://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname>
    <item>
      <title>Is That Email Really From NAR? How to Know</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/H9w1OPkDXQk/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/03/14/is-that-email-really-from-nar-how-to-know/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[2019 national NAR ad campaign]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NAR email scams]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[That's Who We R]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice for Real Estate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14416</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Once in a while you might get an email that looks like it&#8217;s from NAR but really isn&#8217;t. Like so many other phishing scams, these emails try to look like they&#8217;re official correspondence from a trusted source so they can get one of two things from you: personal data or credit card info. How do [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>Once in a while you might get an email that <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=278">looks like it&#8217;s from NAR</a> but really isn&#8217;t. Like so many other phishing scams, these emails try to look like they&#8217;re official correspondence from a trusted source so they can get one of two things from you: personal data or credit card info.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4"><img class="alignleft wp-image-14422" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2019/03/scams.jpg" alt="" width="301" height="169" /></a></p>
<p>How do you know if it&#8217;s really from NAR? Here are a few ways to check.</p>
<p>First, look at the return email address. If it says something like, &#8220;NAR-yahoo.com,&#8221; it&#8217;s not from NAR. NAR email only comes from the realtors.org address. Second, hover your cursor over any file attachments or links or buttons. When you do that, a box will open that provides the location of the file. If it&#8217;s from NAR, the path will make that clear. If it&#8217;s not, it will consist of all sorts of baffling letters and numbers, because the sender is using obscure platforms.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also helpful to know NAR never asks for donations on behalf of individuals. Any donations it seeks is through the REALTORS® Relief Foundation and these are for broad causes, like relief after a tornado, hurricane, fire, or earthquake.</p>
<p>Tips for identifying scams that try to exploit NAR are in the latest <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=278">Voice for Real Estate</a> news video. The video walks you through what to look for and also points to resources at nar.realtor to get more detailed guidance.</p>
<p>The video also looks at why the latest moves by the Federal Reserve could <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=350">help home sales</a> just as the spring weather arrives, what steps Congress can take to <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=112">ease affordability woes</a> home buyers are facing, and what <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=205">competitive factors</a> are brokerage firms facing today.</p>
<p>The video also looks at NAR&#8217;s new <a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4?t=17">national ad campaign</a>, which puts the focus on how the Code of Ethics differentiates real estate agents from REALTORS®.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/XXyqEe7KLs4">Access the video. </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/03/14/is-that-email-really-from-nar-how-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/03/14/is-that-email-really-from-nar-how-to-know/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Clients Invest in Real Estate Tax-Free, and Boost Your Sales</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/whB9H1FYG7U/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/01/24/help-clients-invest-in-real-estate-tax-free-and-boost-your-sales/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 19:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[contentsponsor]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[retirement]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[self-directed IRAs]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Entrust Group]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14407</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[“Time is money” says the proverb, but in real estate, it’s a struggle to have enough time in your day to close more sales. Chances are, most of your clients have an IRA for their retirement savings, which can be used to invest in real estate. With the help of a Real Estate IRA, you [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.theentrustgroup.com/real-estate-ira-report-awareness-lp?utm_campaign=5%20Steps%20to%20Investing%20in%20Real%20Estate%20with%20a%20SDIRA%20Report&amp;utm_source=Realtor&amp;utm_medium=Content%20Promotion%20January%202019"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-14409" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2019/01/300x250-REALTOR-Ad-2019.jpg" alt="The Entrust Group" width="300" height="250" /></a>“Time is money” says the proverb, but in real estate, it’s a struggle to have enough time in your day to close more sales. Chances are, most of your clients have an IRA for their retirement savings, which can be used to invest in real estate. With the help of a Real Estate IRA, you can sell more investment properties using your existing database, generate more referrals and repeat business. Talk to your clients about the advantages of investing their IRA funds in real estate. Having that conversation is a great way to reconnect with clients who may not be ready to buy or sell their house, but might benefit from buying an investment property in an IRA to boost their retirement savings. They will thank you and you will reap the rewards! Real Estate IRA investors will tell others about their experience. We know … Entrust’s clients are our #1 referral source.</p>
<p>Stand out from the competition by educating yourself about Real Estate IRAs and become a valuable resource for your clients. Tap into the $7+ trillion retirement wealth market by showing your clients how to invest in real estate tax-free. Who else would they choose to represent them in buying property for their self-directed IRA?</p>
<p>Our “<a href="https://www.theentrustgroup.com/real-estate-ira-report-awareness-lp?utm_campaign=5%20Steps%20to%20Investing%20in%20Real%20Estate%20with%20a%20SDIRA%20Report&amp;utm_source=Realtor&amp;utm_medium=Content%20Promotion%20January%202019">5 Steps to Investing in Real Estate with a Self-Directed IRA</a>” guide will walk you through the real estate investment process. Real estate agents and clients alike can utilize these steps to invest in real estate using a self-directed IRA with The Entrust Group.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><strong>Editor’s note:</strong> This is a sponsored post from The Entrust Group, a financial services company focusing on real estate investment.</em></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/01/24/help-clients-invest-in-real-estate-tax-free-and-boost-your-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2019/01/24/help-clients-invest-in-real-estate-tax-free-and-boost-your-sales/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Military Base or Prison in Your Rural Town? You Just Got a Big Real Estate Win</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/YacBe41VPqw/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/12/27/big-military-base-or-prison-in-your-rural-town-you-just-got-a-big-real-estate-win/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Bob Turner Southern Properties]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[George Ratiu]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Kathy McQuilkin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Lawrence Yun]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Nick D'Ambroisia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[rural community definition]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[rural home loans]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice for Real Estate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[wire fraud in real estate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[WOTUS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14394</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Prisons and military bases are commonly located outside small, rural towns and often they&#8217;re the biggest employers and economic drivers around. But that’s been a double-edged sword—until now. Prisons and military bases currently count toward an area’s population, putting many communities over the threshold of eligibility for federal Rural Housing Service (RHS) programs. A town [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>Prisons and military bases are commonly located outside small, rural towns and often they&#8217;re the biggest employers and economic drivers around. But that’s been a double-edged sword—until now.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE"><img class="alignleft wp-image-14396" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/12/VRE-93-image.jpg" alt="" width="301" height="169" /></a>Prisons and military bases currently count toward an area’s population, putting many communities over the threshold of eligibility for federal Rural Housing Service (RHS) programs. A town with a population greater than 35,000 isn’t considered rural under RHS guidelines, even if the area meets other criteria, such as a shortage of credit opportunities that are widely available in more populous areas.</p>
<p>However, under a change in the big farm bill that the U.S. Congress recently passed—which the National Association of REALTORS® supports—only a portion of a prison or military base population will count against the area’s population total. That means more small towns can qualify for RHS programs.</p>
<p>Access to RHS programs, which provide safe and affordable mortgages for rural communities, is a lifeline for many homeowners. Importantly, financing through such programs is underwritten using criteria that recognizes the unique characteristics of rural property, such as the presence of other structures on the property or the absence of public services.</p>
<p>The farm bill includes a broader win for rural housing: The population threshold of 35,000 to qualify for RHS programs won’t change until 2030. It was expected to rise in 2020, along with new Census figures, but NAR and other groups asked that the change be delayed because so many communities stood to lose their rural eligibility. This positive development for rural housing is <a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE?t=230">a top story</a> in the latest <a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE">Voice for Real Estate</a> video from NAR.</p>
<p>The video also covers <a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE?t=143">a proposed rule</a> for determining which bodies of water should be regulated under the Clean Water Act. NAR is optimistic that the proposal provides long-sought clarity on the types of bodies of water covered, especially when it comes to small, non-navigable pools that are often seasonal. The video also looks at <a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE?t=18">efforts by NAR and the FBI</a> to reduce the incidence of wire fraud in real estate, the popularity of charitable giving and volunteering among REALTORS®, and what to expect with sales and leasing in 2019 if the stock market remains volatile.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/WLz4N81wPYE">Access and share the video. </a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/12/27/big-military-base-or-prison-in-your-rural-town-you-just-got-a-big-real-estate-win/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/12/27/big-military-base-or-prison-in-your-rural-town-you-just-got-a-big-real-estate-win/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Ethics Changes That Can Impact Your Real Estate Work</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/-jTw20degDc/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/11/21/2-ethics-changes-that-can-impact-your-real-estate-work/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 20:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MLS Policy Statement 7.73]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NAR Code of Ethics]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice for Real Estate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14385</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The NAR Board of Directors a few weeks ago made a few small but important changes to MLS and other rules to improve cooperation among brokers and reinforce the importance of associations&#8217; ethics procedures. Here&#8217;s a brief recap. You can also learn about them in the latest Voice for Real Estate video. Proceeding With Ethics [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>The NAR Board of Directors a few weeks ago made a few small but important changes to MLS and other rules to improve cooperation among brokers and reinforce the importance of associations&#8217; ethics procedures. Here&#8217;s a brief recap. You can also learn about them in the latest <a href="https://youtu.be/MIU6d7kYkDs?t=5m5s">Voice for Real Estate</a> video.<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/MIU6d7kYkDs?t=5m5s"><img class="alignleft wp-image-14387" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/11/VRE-92-image.jpg" alt="" width="230" height="130" /></a></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Proceeding With Ethics Complaints When Criminal Litigation is Also Involved</strong><br />
Associations are allowed to continue to process ethics complaints when there is criminal litigation pending that involves the same facts and circumstances.</li>
</ol>
<p>2.<strong> Enforcing Cooperation via MLS Through Written Certification of Offer Presentations</strong><br />
The Board amended MLS Policy Statement 7.73 regarding the rights of cooperating brokers in the presentation of offers.</p>
<p>The policy reinforces cooperation and brings MLS policy in line with the Code of Ethics. Under the rule, listing brokers will be required to provide written affirmation or notification to cooperating brokers on the disposition of their offer. The requirement gives associations the ability to impose disciplinary action against a listing broker who fails to present either written confirmation that the offer was presented or evidence that the seller waived the obligation to have the offer presented.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/MIU6d7kYkDs?t=5m5s">Access the video. </a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.nar.realtor/about-nar/governing-documents/code-of-ethics/2018-code-of-ethics-standards-of-practice">NAR Code of Ethics and Standards of Practice. </a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.nar.realtor/about-nar/policies/mls-policy">MLS governing documents. </a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/11/21/2-ethics-changes-that-can-impact-your-real-estate-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/11/21/2-ethics-changes-that-can-impact-your-real-estate-work/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Follow Up: Effective Follow-up Communication Techniques</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/Nrz-Ef-KahU/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/12/the-art-of-follow-up-effective-follow-up-communication-techniques/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 15:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[contentsponsor]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14369</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Strategic outreach, whether by phone, email or text, is key to building rapport and credibility with prospects, staying top of mind in the search for a home, and encouraging clients to follow through with the sale. But outreach, by itself, doesn&#8217;t close deals. If you&#8217;re contacting leads regularly, but still having trouble reaching your sales [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>Strategic outreach, whether by phone, email or text, is key to building rapport and credibility with prospects, staying top of mind in the search for a home, and encouraging clients to follow through with the sale. But outreach, by itself, doesn&#8217;t close deals.</p>
<p><a href="//content.firepoint.net/effective-communication-templates-download?utm_campaign=FollowUp&amp;utm_source=RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromotion&amp;utm_content=OctContentPromo"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-14372" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/10/RealtorMag_80x80.jpg" alt="" width="167" height="167" /></a>If you&#8217;re contacting leads regularly, but still having trouble reaching your sales goals, you may be using the wrong outreach methods for the wrong types of communication.</p>
<p>Find ideas for improving your outreach metods in a new guide, <a href="https://content.firepoint.net/effective-communication-templates-download?utm_campaign=FollowUp&amp;utm_source=RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromotion&amp;utm_content=OctContentPromo">The Art of Follow Up: Effective Follow-up Communication Techniques.</a></p>
<p>Great for team leads looking to improve their coaching skills and agents looking to communicate more effectively, this guide provides a deep dive into the different outreach methods, when to use them, best practices and effective sample templates.</p>
<p>Editor&#8217;s note: This is a sponsored post from Firepoint Solutions, a company that offers a customer relationship management (CRM) tool for real estate professionals.</p>
<p><a href="//content.firepoint.net/effective-communication-templates-download?utm_campaign=FollowUp&amp;utm_source=RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromotion&amp;utm_content=OctContentPromo"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-14374" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/10/RealtorMag_600x500.jpg" alt="" width="312" height="260" /></a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/12/the-art-of-follow-up-effective-follow-up-communication-techniques/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/12/the-art-of-follow-up-effective-follow-up-communication-techniques/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Factor 20% Deduction Into Your 2018 Estimated Quarterly Payments</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/g2k6902_kAM/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/01/how-to-factor-20-deduction-into-your-2018-estimated-quarterly-payments/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 13:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[20% business income deduction]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[pass-through entities]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice for Real Estate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14357</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The big win for real estate in last year&#8217;s tax reform law is the new 20 percent business income deduction. You take it on your net pass-through income. Pass-through income is what most real estate professionals earn. If you&#8217;re an independent contractor or if you&#8217;ve structured yourself as a sole proprietor, your income is considered [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>The big win for real estate in last year&#8217;s tax reform law is the new 20 percent business income deduction. You take it on your  net pass-through income. Pass-through income is what most real estate professionals earn. If you&#8217;re an independent contractor or if you&#8217;ve structured yourself as a sole proprietor, your income is considered pass-through because you calculate your taxes on the individual, rather than the business, side of your tax filing. </p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/Cmthe750gsk?t=1m41s"><img src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/10/VRE-90-image.jpg" alt="" width="230" height="130" class="alignleft wp-image-14359" /></a>Being able to take 20 percent off your income is potentially a big money saver for you and 2018 is the first year you can apply it. That means for the last three quarters, you have had the opportunity to calculate your deduction as part of your estimated payments. </p>
<p>As with any new tax provision, there are questions about applying that deduction in your estimated taxes, and the IRS hasn&#8217;t issued final rules yet. But there are a few things you can do. </p>
<p>First, you want to make sure your accountant is aware of the deduction. Second, you can take the safe-harbor approach and calculate your estimated quarterly payments based on what your income was last year. If you do that, even if you&#8217;ve underestimated your taxes come April of 2019, when  you have to settle up your payments, you won&#8217;t get penalized or have interest payments imposed on you. Third, you can choose to calculate your actual payment rather than use last year as a guide. The risk here, though, if you end up underpaying, is you could face a penalty and interest payments. (Although you might be eligible for a penalty waiver depending on your tax-filing history.)</p>
<p>Whatever you do, make sure you have a professional accountant or tax attorney guide you. The IRS is expected to release its final rules before the end of the year. When it does, it will likely release new or modified forms to help you calculate the new deduction. </p>
<p>There are other potentially favorable provisions in the new tax law, starting with the reduction in tax rates. All of the brackets are lower now, so at a minimum, you face lower tax rates on your income. On the negative side, the deduction for business entertainment costs is gone and there&#8217;s ambiguity in deducting business meal costs when those costs are wrapped up in your entertainment expenses. The IRS should have guidance on that soon. </p>
<p>On the 20 percent business income deduction, there&#8217;s common-sense advice in a new <a href="https://magazine.realtor/law-and-ethics/feature/article/2018/09/how-the-20-business-income-deduction-applies-to-you">Q&amp;A</a> published by REALTOR® Magazine. It&#8217;s based on a conversation with Peter Baker, a veteran CPA whose practice specializes in helping real estate agents and brokers. <a href="https://magazine.realtor/law-and-ethics/feature/article/2018/09/how-the-20-business-income-deduction-applies-to-you">You can access that Q&amp;A here.</a></p>
<p>The latest <a href="https://youtu.be/Cmthe750gsk?t=1m41s">Voice for Real Estate</a> news video from NAR also tackles the 20-percent deduction issue. <a href="https://youtu.be/Cmthe750gsk?t=1m41s">Watch that segment here.</a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/01/how-to-factor-20-deduction-into-your-2018-estimated-quarterly-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/10/01/how-to-factor-20-deduction-into-your-2018-estimated-quarterly-payments/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarity on Deductibility of Meal Expenses May Be Coming</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/xoLA1am1s08/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/09/28/clarity-on-deductibility-of-meal-expenses-may-be-coming/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Silverstein]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Managing Your Business]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Taxes]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14354</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[You may have seen a report today in The Wall Street Journal (subscription and login required) stating that the Internal Revenue Service is working on guidance that would clarify the deductibility of expenses for client meals under the new tax law. According to the report, this guidance is expected to say that the cost of [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>You may have seen <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/order-the-steak-client-meal-deductions-will-be-allowed-1538132401">a report today in The Wall Street Journal</a> <em>(subscription and login required)</em> stating that the Internal Revenue Service is working on guidance that would clarify the deductibility of expenses for client meals under the <a href="https://www.nar.realtor/tax-reform/the-tax-cuts-and-jobs-act-what-it-means-for-homeowners-and-real-estate-professionals">new tax law</a>. According to the report, this guidance is expected to say that the cost of business meals will be 50 percent deductible. That could include expenses for food purchased at events defined as entertainment, such as ballgames, as long as the cost of the food is documented separately, the report says.</p>
<p>The tax law passed last December made clear that the cost of the entertainment itself, which formerly was 50 percent deductible, is no longer deductible as a business expense, but left open the question of whether meals for clients, even at events that are primarily business-related, would still be partially deductible.</p>
<p>This rule clarification is of particular interest to real estate professionals, because many provide food at open houses or receptions for clients and prospective clients. “Unfortunately, this falls under a gray area, and we will not know for sure until the IRS issues guidance,” says Evan Liddiard, a CPA and NAR’s senior policy representative for federal taxation.</p>
<p>Linda de Marlor, president of Tax-Masters Inc., an accounting firm in Rockville, Md., that helps real estate professionals manage their taxes, says she believes that the cost of food served at an event intended specifically to provide information to clients will be deductible under the new tax law. “If I hold a seminar and I serve food at the seminar for the people who come, then that’s education, and I can deduct it,” de Marlor says.</p>
<p>Also, note that even if the IRS settles the question of whether business meals are still partially deductible, you’ll still need to ensure that these expenses are reasonable. Claiming a deduction for food expenses that are considered excessively high could cause the cost of the food to be deemed entertainment instead of a meal expense—and the deduction to be disallowed as a result.</p>
<p>As with any tax-related matter, real estate professionals should speak with a qualified tax advisor before making any decisions regarding the deductibility of meal expenses. NAR will continue to advocate for members as the government implements the new tax law, and will provide further information about this topic following any guidance issued by the IRS.</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/09/28/clarity-on-deductibility-of-meal-expenses-may-be-coming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/09/28/clarity-on-deductibility-of-meal-expenses-may-be-coming/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rule of 3: Communicating to Grow Your Business</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/22-dEoteVJg/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/28/the-rule-of-3-communicating-to-grow-your-business/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 18:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[contentsponsor]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Firepoint]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Rule of 3]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14341</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[When you contact clients, make sure to offer something of value in the conversation so they don’t see it as a nuisance call. Content sponsor Firepoint, a real estate CRM company, has released The Rule of 3, a guidebook to help you create a communications strategy focused on increasing leads. Here’s what the company says [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://content.firepoint.net/rule-of-three-download?utm_source=NAR-RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromo&amp;utm_campaign=RuleOf3"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-14342" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/08/80-x-80-RO3-01.png" alt="" width="334" height="334" /></a>When you contact clients, make sure to offer something of value in the conversation so they don’t see it as a nuisance call. Content sponsor Firepoint, a real estate CRM company, has released <a href="https://content.firepoint.net/rule-of-three-download?utm_source=NAR-RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromo&amp;utm_campaign=RuleOf3"><em>The Rule of 3</em></a>, a guidebook to help you create a communications strategy focused on increasing leads. Here’s what the company says about the guide:</p>
<p><em>The Rule of 3</em> is a communication strategy for new leads. It’s based on the principle of contacting new leads three times a day for three days, three times a week for three weeks, and three times a month for three months. While on the surface it feels like too much communication, it’s a proven approach that many top agents and teams use to drive their businesses. The guide lays out the details to implement this strategy effectively so that prospective clients see the communication as helpful and valuable, and not as a nuisance. This is the key to converting more leads into clients and growing a real estate business.</p>
<p><a href="https://content.firepoint.net/rule-of-three-download?utm_source=NAR-RealtorMag&amp;utm_medium=ContentPromo&amp;utm_campaign=RuleOf3">Get your copy of <em>The Rule of 3</em>.</a></p>
<p><em>This is a sponsored content post. REALTOR® Magazine is promoting the book but has not reviewed or endorsed its content.</em></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/28/the-rule-of-3-communicating-to-grow-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/28/the-rule-of-3-communicating-to-grow-your-business/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Win for REALTORS® on IRS Guidance for 20% Income Deduction</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/LyKRD7r5rHY/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/09/big-win-for-realtors-on-irs-guidance-for-20-income-deduction/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[IRS 199A rule]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[tax reform]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14329</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[If you were tuned to the news Aug. 8 you might have heard the IRS released proposed regulations on the new 20 percent business income deduction for pass through businesses. IRS summary with link to FAQ. Proposed rules. The deduction was part of the big tax reform law Congress passed at the end of last [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>If you were tuned to the news Aug. 8 you might have heard the IRS released proposed regulations on the new 20 percent business income deduction for pass through businesses.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-issues-proposed-regulations-on-new-20-percent-deduction-for-passthrough-businesses">IRS summary with link to FAQ.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/reg-107892-18.pdf">Proposed rules.</a></p>
<p>The deduction was part of the big tax reform law Congress passed at the end of last year and it was a huge win for REALTORS®. But it was unclear who would be eligible for the deduction. Now that proposed regulations are out, it’s clear the new deduction will be available to a wide range of real estate professionals.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-issues-proposed-regulations-on-new-20-percent-deduction-for-passthrough-businesses"><img class="alignright wp-image-14330" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/08/t.png" alt="" width="331" height="167" /></a></p>
<p>Under the new law, individual owners of sole proprietorships, including independent contractors, and owners of S corporations, LLCs, or partnerships can take the 20 percent deduction on their net qualified (that is, ordinary, non-investment ) business income. The calculation will depend on income thresholds, what type of business you own, and how you meet certain wage and qualified property tests. But the basic structure is very favorable to you as a small business or independent contractor.</p>
<p>REALTORS® were integral to the favorable interpretation in the proposed rules. Your association made a forceful case—both in a detailed letter it sent on June 19 and in a face-to-face meeting with IRS officials in early August—that certain limitations on specified service businesses were not intended by Congress to apply to real estate professionals. And that’s the interpretation the IRS has ended up taking.</p>
<p>As an Aug. 7 Bloomberg News article says, the National Association of REALTORS® “met with OMB (Office of Management and Budget) and Treasury Department officials to discuss proposed rules outlining computation of the new write-off for pass-throughs.”</p>
<p>The new deduction is available for tax years beginning after Dec. 31, 2017. You’ll be able to claim it for the first time on the 2018 federal income tax return you file next year.</p>
<p>Look for detailed NAR guidance by mid-September. It’s a complicated provision and how it works for you will depend on many factors unique to your business structure and your income. As always, consult with your accountant or tax attorney on how this deduction should be applied in your situation.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-issues-proposed-regulations-on-new-20-percent-deduction-for-passthrough-businesses">IRS summary with link to FAQ.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/reg-107892-18.pdf">Proposed rules.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.nar.realtor/tax-reform">NAR tax reform resources.</a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/09/big-win-for-realtors-on-irs-guidance-for-20-income-deduction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/09/big-win-for-realtors-on-irs-guidance-for-20-income-deduction/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You Competing for a Real Estate Pie That’s Not Growing?</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SpeakingOfRealEstate/~3/cdJ3_OqfLIA/</link>
      <comments>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/06/are-you-competing-for-a-real-estate-pie-thats-not-growing/#comments</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 14:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Freedman]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[2018 real estate investment opportunities]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[flood insurance extension]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Realtor income]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice for Real Estate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/?p=14315</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Unemployment is low and the economy is growing&#8212;more than 4 percent in the last quarter&#8212;but  home sales are actually going down for many real estate agents. The typical agent in the last year worked on 11 transaction sides, down from 12 sides the previous year. What&#8217;s going on? For starters, the inventory crunch is holding [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<p>Unemployment is low and the economy is growing&#8212;more than 4 percent in the last quarter&#8212;but  home sales are actually going down for many real estate agents. The typical agent in the last year worked on 11 transaction sides, down from 12 sides the previous year.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU"><img class="alignleft wp-image-14321" src="http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/files/2018/08/VRE-88-image.jpg" alt="" width="301" height="169" /></a>What&#8217;s going on? For starters, the inventory crunch is holding markets back. Particularly in the lower price points, there just aren&#8217;t many homes for sale. But there are also more agents, at least among those who are REALTORS®. NAR&#8217;s membership grew to 1.3 million last year from 1.22 million the previous year. That means more agents are competing for a pie that&#8217;s not growing. About a third of NAR members have two or fewer years of experience.</p>
<p>There are plenty of positives coming out of this. For one, the value of home sales is rising, so with each sale, agents stand to make a bit more. NAR estimates that price appreciation is about 5 percent a year nationally. NAR Chief Economist Lawrence Yun would like to see prices ease so they&#8217;re more in line with wage increases, maybe around 3 percent. But as long as demand exceeds supply, price pressure will be upward.</p>
<p>Another positive is the <a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU?t=2m53s">increase in younger people</a> coming into the profession. Although the median age of real estate professionals is inching up, from 54 to 55 last year, the profession is nevertheless seeing more young people. And that&#8217;s good for the future of real estate.</p>
<p>These and other industry trends are looked at in the latest Voice for Real Estate news video from NAR.</p>
<p>The video looks at the <a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU?t=1m9s">opportunity agents and investors have</a> buying small commercial properties in smaller markets across the United States. For years, the focus has been on big properties in big markets like Chicago and New York, but these markets are now seeing investors pulling back. Still untapped is the opportunity in the bulk of the country, says Hugh Kelly, a commercial real estate analyst who also teaches at Fordham University. &#8220;You&#8217;re not going to find assets worth $1.5 million or $2 million [that you can compete for in Manhattan],&#8221; says Kelly. &#8220;You&#8217;re going to find them in Fresno, Kansas City, and Louisville.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kelly gave a talk to NAR researchers last week on what he&#8217;s seeing in commercial markets around the country.</p>
<p>The video also looks at why global investors are <a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU?t=2m18s">pulling back on U.S. home purchases.</a> Last year they invested $121 billion in residential markets here. That&#8217;s a big number but it&#8217;s 20 percent less than what they invested the previous year. Are homes becoming less attractive to them? NAR Chief Economist Lawrence Yun says there are many factors at play, including a stronger dollar, but it&#8217;s also the case that global buyers surged into U.S. residential markets two years ago, and so now were seeing a pullback from that.</p>
<p>Other segments in the video look at the recent extension of federal flood insurance and the upcoming <a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU?t=4m52s">Real Estate Innovation, Opportunity,  and Investment Summit</a> in San Francisco later this month. The flood insurance extension is until the end of November. That gives lawmakers time to see if they can find agreement on much-needed program reforms to make the insurance more financially sound. The iOi summit is NAR&#8217;s first formal effort to put tech people and venture capitalists into the same room as real estate executives and brokers so everyone can work together to design products and services and business models that benefit consumers by helping real estate professionals become even more powerful agents on their clients&#8217; behalf.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/jfmXE-CFCOU">Access and share the video.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/06/are-you-competing-for-a-real-estate-pie-thats-not-growing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
      <feedburner:origLink>http://speakingofrealestate.blogs.realtor.org/2018/08/06/are-you-competing-for-a-real-estate-pie-thats-not-growing/</feedburner:origLink>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.457 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2019-03-14 09:59:35 -->
<!-- Compression = gzip -->
